Breakfast Club morning everybody is DJ
envy Angela Guiche Alamein the guy we
are the Breakfast Club we got a special
guest in the building yes indeed
heard her name in the last couple of
months and weeks all over the news we
not done there we're not doing that
which is out right now yes
Amanda sales good morning you know
they're already like I see back on the
show again
they always got her up there something
exactly new book out right now cool
small doses that's right now I know the
title of your podcast and small doses
let me say something yes I don't want
this to be an easy interview oh you
think this is gonna be easy
I don't just telling you I don't want it
to be okay
well because you love me like so I think
sometimes people are like well they go
easy on her because they family or
whatever no okay so let's ride on a
onesie I'm ready for okay I just want
you know because I I really have been
doing like press all out the wazoo this
year okay and I feel like that sometimes
ends up like doing bad or good for you
whatever but when I come here I don't
consider it press like I come here and I
for consider it like conversation
amongst family conversation amongst
family but I consider it almost like a
forum so I just wanted to put that
disclaimer out there that like come at
me bro it is hard it is hard when you
interview your friends though because
it's like I know what how we talked off
there and we should keep that off there
okay just making sure
all right however you know I think that
there are things that may need to be
addressed gotcha
and I am ready to address whatever so
we'll get to that but first small doses
my book is so exciting why is why do you
small doses why the podcast me small
doses why the book because they don't
seem like you do anything small well be
I'm a truth teller and the truth hurts
and so a lot of times we need it in
small doses God and so you know I try to
throughout the book give it to you in
different sizes so there's essays
there's stories there's blurbs there's
lists there's poems but at the end of
the day it's basically a life guide for
anybody who's socially conscious and
aware and trying to get there if they
ain't they're already trying to get
there and I do that for humor and
through common sense
now we also every time you come up here
you always talk about people that don't
like you or they always say it has
something negative to say why do you
think that is do you think they can only
take you in small doses oh yeah I think
there's a number of reasons if we're
being honest like I think I think some
people don't like me for the reasons
that they don't like themselves I think
some people don't like me because of how
I've approached certain situations with
them personally I think some people
don't like me because of information or
you know gossip that they've heard from
other sources I think some people don't
like me because I'm very light-skinned
and they feel I have no place to speak
about the black women experience or
about the black experience or to the
black experience I think some people
don't like me because I'm a woman with a
very strong point of view and an opinion
and what they consider to be someone
being stubborn is really someone who's
just sure of herself I think some people
don't like me because I may reflect
something that they desire that they
have yet to like make happen I think
that there's a number of reasons that
people don't like me and what's crazy is
that it was a really long like when I
like what I've experienced recently with
this internet [ __ ] like it could take
you out like if I was somebody with a
different set of people around me or if
maybe my chemical mind was different
like my the way that my chemical balance
in my brain was different like I may not
have made it out of that social media is
bad for your mental health it'll
definitely Drive you to that brink at
times 1,000% and because it's like it
[ __ ] with your perception of reality
yes you know and like it can be really
trippy when an entire school
of energy you know when you at church
and maybe like okay let's all pray for
for sister seals you know and send our
energy you know what that what that
really is is like let's all as a group
send energy in a direction towards
somebody for healing right because
there's a powerful there's a power and
energy so when they when you go viral in
the wrong way on these internets it's
like the adverse of that it's literally
like let's all send toxicity towards
this person in the same direction and
it's very very easy for people to say
things like why do you care or for
people to say things like I mean you
famous what you expect or people to say
like why can't you just ignore it and
it's like well one I'm not a sociopath
so you feel I feel probably an empath
because I am a true empath so and even
if I want to like protect myself from
those things I still have a
consciousness and a self-awareness about
like well let me make sure that I'm not
doing the things like maybe let me make
let me do a self check but it gets so
overwhelming and people take so much joy
in and pulling that trigger it's it's
it's like it becomes frightening to you
that like why would people want you to
hurt so bad well a lot of that is
because of what you said earliest
because of what you're doing you know
I'm saying you got HBO stand-up specials
and you on I'm sure you're putting a
black and selling out and you got booked
I don't think that way and that's so
frightening to me that we think that way
that like someone's doing too much
that's that's always been the issue with
Amanda she's just too much but do you
think people don't understand your grind
never seen your grind don't understand
what you've been through 1,000%
you know mmm you know like I you know I
have worked my ass off mm-hmm so I don't
know and and I think that for people to
say they don't understand my grind is
like well it's out there you know like
if anything is documented like I've been
at this for a long time but I think you
know a lot of that stuff I can shake off
but when it's coming out all at once
like you have to somehow figure out how
to compartmentalize it and it can feel
indomitable like it really can feel like
you just can't get past it and I was
alone I almost let these [ __ ]
make me forget Who I am
because we live in a in an era where I'm
really I'm really frightened in general
for the fact that I think a lot of
especially within the black community I
think a lot of us can't tell the
difference between our villains and our
warriors hmm I think that a lot of us
are not able to tell the difference
between fact and fiction especially on
the internet on the Internet I think
that we are in an era where we are we
are almost scarily obsessed with like
opinion based blogs versus fact source
journalism and that is very scary
because people make their opinions based
on a number of things right and we live
in a nation where media right now is
controlled by money by cliques so like
I've been the victim of literally just
someone making up some [ __ ] just so
people will click so they've made money
off of lying about me and that is like
an insane thought process to me because
I am so about just like keeping it a
book in a like even if you feel like oh
she's always negative it's like but I'm
addressing something that is negative in
order for us to get to the positive like
that's actually the journey I'm taking
and so sometimes I get frustrated that
that's being miss misnomer like this is
my way of love but we live in an era
where there's just a wild obsession with
creating conflict versus quelling it yes
and it's it's like I had such an
awakening in these past two weeks
because I couldn't believe how people
took something that was so basic to me
which is like don't put each other in
wild situations for no reason other than
our own personal reasons like we got to
think bigger we got to think brighter we
got to think broader and it turned into
like [ __ ] her she's a [ __ ] and it's
like
where y'all leaving getting this from
like I'm a [ __ ] because I say something
that makes you uncomfortable like I
didn't eat a baby I didn't [ __ ] your man
I didn't [ __ ] on your mother like I
don't I don't really even babies
I'm just saying so much I'm just like I
I don't know I don't know how being
unabashedly smart has become such a
villainous thing I don't know how being
unabashedly like on point with how I
want my brand how I want my work how I
want my quality control to be how I want
my space and my the men in my life to
behave around me I want my friends I
don't know when that became like [ __ ]
huh you know like anybody less than [ __ ]
to say about me I'm like if you was in
the situation I was in
when this person was they talking you
would have done the same thing that I
said you would probably said the same
[ __ ] to that person that I said and I
just think that it I'm getting emotional
but the point of the matter is this a
lot of people Miss nomer anger and I
like a lot of people know my passion is
anger and I have a shirt like I have a
whole thing that says like I'm not
hostile I'm just passionate and I think
so many black women we identify with
this but then we'll point the finger at
each other and that hurts me and I think
so many black men like our misnomer nest
Dougs
you know for for being able to express
themselves or you know being able to
have you're so articulate you know and
it's like oh my god and it's like when
we acknowledge when we see that in other
women sometimes it's like we're not
supposed to do that so have you ever
have you ever looked at cuz you know
just this narrative about Amanda Sears
been around for a long time yeah Amanda
Steel's got a bad attitude yeah Amanda
sills is difficult to work with
Amanda sills is just a terrible person
have you ever step step step back and
said okay what did I do in this
situation that made people feel that we
do that all the time so I think for one
I think if we look at like the hundred
percent of that there's probably about
5% of those situations where like ya owe
you an apology and I've done that you
know um I think for the rest of the
folks and this is not and it's not even
it's this is not conceited cockiness
this is somebody who is really sat here
and looked at this
I think really like one people do not
like to be corrected mm-hmm even if
they're working for you even though were
you and they're doing things like they
don't like to be corrected they don't
like to be corrected by women that's a
fact and there's a thing where if you're
the talent like people don't want to
hear it from you like even if your
manager or your publicist or your agent
says the exact same thing as you it's
like yeah but you're not allowed to say
it
because that's not the rules and
everybody knows like I don't play by the
rules like the the type of person I am
to create the art that I do I would
never be a rule follower like the two
things don't happen in the same space so
in terms of like am i a terrible person
that's absolutely ridiculous and absurd
like and if we're measuring that I'm
like well what kind of meat are y'all
measuring that on like so there's people
that we can acknowledge our 100%
terrible people are Kelly is a terrible
person mm-hmm
you know so I'm so I'm our Kelly now
like the [ __ ] out of here that's but
that's the stuff that trips me cuz I'm
like where do we go how do we get this
far we're like our meter is so disparate
that we only have like the saint of
Beyonce and the terrible of our Kelly
and there's no middle you know and I
think context matters in situations like
that people don't have context
hey Kyle Kelly is the extreme of just
being a terrible human just because he's
terrible you like what you do I think
they say I don't know maybe it's what
you're talking about you work with
somebody you correct them are you
telling me viola you might wouldn't I
doesn't when they were living fast I
don't know language but okay so I'll
give you a situation like I have
approached someone and said listen I
just want you to know anybody talking
about you behind your back everybody in
here has been talking about you behind
your back
for this particular situation I know who
that person is and I'm gonna come and
keep it a buck with you because
everybody's talking about you behind
your back and I don't want nobody to do
that to me so I'm not gonna have them do
that to you correct and so here's your
opportunity to let you know one if this
is true I hope that you possibly shift
from the decision you're making because
it could have negative ramifications for
a number of people including yourself
too if it's not true I hope that you
understand that people do think it's
true in
it may be it may be on your plate to try
and change you know the perception right
I was told you shouldn't do that don't
insert yourself in situations like that
because you have now brought it onto
yourself and I'm like I'm not that kind
of person like I break up domestic
violence fights in public like I'm the
I'm a crusader like I'm the green beret
like I was the kid who was you know all
with like flat-chested and made fun of
like I've been bullied for everything
like I didn't bully for your I've been
bullied by the white girls to be in
black I've been bullied by the black
girls for not being black enough you
know I've been bullied for all type of
[ __ ] I've been bullied for being smart
I've been bullied for being loud I've
been believed for being West Indian you
name it so I do have it in me like I
want to protect people how much of that
how much of that trauma still exist in
because it could be a defense mechanism
you might walk you wish a [ __ ]
would person Amanda I am a wish a
[ __ ] would person 1000% so is my
momma so that's definitely a part of it
and that's the work I do and I work on
myself all the time I'm in therapy and
it's just like sometimes it's just that
the internet will trick you into
thinking that the work you're doing
isn't good enough it's not like the work
is not working the work is not working
look at yourself yes and I said this on
big boy like yo if you're not careful
you will let the people that know the
least about you convince you that you
don't know you and that is a mindful
that is a mindful it's a mindfuck like
it's scary that people could take you
there I have a cat I can't cry okay it's
scary that people I can't cry the cat
eyes that's my [ __ ] short um it was
very precise so you can't you can't let
people take you there but this passion
in this intensity that allows me to like
create incredible work that allows me to
write a whole book you know that allows
me to continuously like put content out
and have opinions on things from a
fact-based plays etc like that intensity
doesn't just go away when people try to
play me nedovic NC doesn't just go away
when I see someone getting played you
know like it's still there like first of
all I'm West Indian so and I'm from
Grenada
it's called the Isle of spice not just
cousin nutmeg
spicy you know we're spicy I saw it
firsthand I was there I was little
simple things like Amanda ordering
drinks from the waitress and they going
back and forth like any about the fight
what's happening here but that's just
how everybody in Grenada is but you see
there was no beef though right she party
drinks so so let's go to the the black
Amy party you gonna jump all the way to
that are you still on insecure see that
NASA people will be like Amanda got a
bad attitude but that was a dumbass
question just a question no but what
happened at the black anybody in a
nutshell I was invited by somebody who
was involved with the party mm-hmm and
so I went to the party with the
intention of being a part of this black
experience and in Hollywood we are so
often like polka dots in a room you know
and I over the weekend like I'd went to
our comedy special party I went to the
NBC party I went to the HBO party and
you know you're there when you mingle
but we party different you know and at
the end of the day like I do feel like
there's a black movement in Hollywood
and I'm a part of it like I am honored
to be a part of it so I was already just
go in there with the inside of like I'm
excited I was telling people to go there
I was literally at other parties like
y'all we need to get out of here and go
celebrate our blackness we need to go
celebrate our blackness and I know
there's people were like yeah but why
would you go if you know there might be
dissension cuz I'm the type of person
who thinks like I literally was saying
to myself like even if you think
something could go left like this is
bigger than that like don't even get
caught up in like that type of [ __ ] like
this is so much bigger than that like
the fact that we have a space go be a
part of that space so I went there to be
a part of that space even though the
president wanna promote is you knew did
not like you
well I feel like as long as the person
who did not like no we're not doing that
but I feel like don't take it easy on me
that's what you want well I'm glad she
didn't say her name I think she said her
name too much oh so I think that there's
I think there's a time and place for
things right so like if it was a
personal party like a birthday party or
something I absolutely would not put
myself in that space but because I was
invited to the party by somebody who was
also involved in planning the party I
thought there to be an understanding
that this is an open space for open love
so I didn't go there thinking like okay
let me bob and weave
I went there like you know I'm not gonna
party with that person anyway correct
it's a big-ass place you know so we've
all been to these and I think a lot of
people don't understand like this is a
work party mmm like it's an industry
event therefore it is a work party and
so I just went there with those
intentions and what there were those
intentions and then I just met I met
some friction at the door and I was
confused as to why I was being denied
entry and so were a number of people
like but why but why but why because I'm
not some I'm not somebody who's like on
the fringe like at this point especially
within the black entertainment space
like I think people have acknowledged I
have like significant contributions to
this space and so why wouldn't I be
allowed to enjoy the other folks that
have significant contributions and share
with them so you think that's a sense of
entitlement no I think it's a sense of
fact mmm it's a black Emmy party for
black entertainment I have my special
was on the Emmy ballot so why would I
I agree with that but I don't ever
approach any situation like I should be
here because of Who I am
like I'm just like brothers they tell me
I can't get it I'll be like I [ __ ] it's
a little different to black Emmy party
people had 20 he said it's not a
birthday party in the Christmas party
people like funny and people like the
[ __ ] on use in an ever so subtle way
sometimes what about themselves feel bad
what about all the people have seen you
outside and we're walking in now nobody
said you know what I'm a ho my girl down
what the [ __ ] is going on well that was
interesting
that wasn't that was a painful lesson um
there were people but there were others
who didn't and I will remember that
forever cuz I'm a cancer but no they
were absolutely individuals I mean I got
in the party because someone who was
involved with the party was like why are
you out here
come inside and brought me in the party
so that's when I say when I see [ __ ]
like she
snuck in the problem like so y'all spent
like weeks making jokes about some [ __ ]
that didn't happen you see but you bum
rush the door I don't even know how to
bum rush now you've not a bum rush we
lived in New York okay
I walked up with one person in my home
girl in real estate that's not a bum
rush okay like no you go if you bum rush
and you come in with a squad you come in
like onyx yeah
like its last days out here no I didn't
bum rush I literally walked up to the
rope and then was let in and then was
told no you got to get out so I was let
in and then told you got to get out was
the person I walked you in at that time
so then somebody came out and walked me
in so we walked in and we we walked in
and I went and stood by the bar cuz at
this point I'm like okay glad that's
over
we went stood by the bar and that's when
a security guard approached me and was
like I'm trying me said we have to ask
you to leave and I was like ask me to
leave
what are we talking about and he was
like yeah and I said find out who wants
me to leave so you found out who wanted
me to leave and he let me know and then
three other security guards approached
and I think that it's real easy to like
read a blog story and where people like
purposely you know leave out details
because it's it's juicier or whatever
but and people think like it was a party
like why she's so stressed about a party
I'm stressed because I'm a black woman
and four men surrounded me to remove me
from somewhere that I belonged that's
why I'm stressed I'm stressed because I
didn't even have a [ __ ] dare with me to
hold me down in that situation I'm
stressed because I know that another
woman has put me in this situation and
that stresses me out for a number of
reasons cuz I'm also stressed out for
her cuz I'm like damn what what are you
dealing with that would cause you so
much pain to put me into so much pain so
I'm there I'm stressed because a
security guard put hands on me and I
can't put hands back because for obvious
reasons so I would love to bombers a
security guard but I can't so so many of
us have been in those situations so many
times where we're helpless we can't we
don't have any
anyway to fight and so you end up just
feeling like worthless and humiliated
you see people around you watching you
in this situation people who you would
have helped in a second do nothing and
you feel like what is this like this is
what I've this is what I've worked and
grinded like my whole [ __ ] to get to to
get to be in these spaces and these safe
spaces and enjoy and celebrate and
there's so to be [ __ ] on like that is a
very multi-layered experience it's a
black thing you posed to feel safe
around your people if you don't feel
safe around your people where do you
feel safe and that's why you know and
that's why I asked you we know you took
it as a joke
I've been secure is because if I'm
outside and I see somebody that I [ __ ]
would I work with outside and they
having a problem well now have a problem
this is another thing like people make
conflict when there isn't I never at any
point said that my co-stars saw me and
decided not to help me I never said that
lady said it was a whole table but that
doesn't mean they saw me at the table
could be back around the corner outside
or Charlamagne oh no you wouldn't you
literally you literally done that yeah
that's not the music in a club no
nobody's partying so my people get in
fast but that's me so I never said that
there's a bunch of [ __ ] I've never done
that I get taken else for all the time
I've never I never said that
you know I've I've never I've had people
do entire videos about like Amanda
Steele's think she's better than black
Americans because she's from the
Caribbean I have never said anything
even remotely resembling that also I'm
black American my father is a [ __ ] from
Boston but you know like the descendant
of slaves from Arkansas what are we
[ __ ] talking about you'll learn that
in small doses
there you go like I have never said I
think I'm prettier than anybody because
I'm light-skinned are you [ __ ] really
like even when we talked about those
narratives it's like how do we get to a
place where we forget that it used to be
legal to rape people in this country and
so a number of us are are just legal to
rape black people anywhere like that was
like a thing so a lot of us are
descendants of that you're basically
tired of being misunderstood I'm so
tired so it is cuz it's because it's
willful it's willful and I'm tired of it
and I'm on here just being honest with
you and Vaughn herbal and I know they're
still gonna be like she a crybaby [ __ ]
y'all because day like everybody is so
afraid to be real and I keep it a buck
all the goddamn time and a lot of the
people that y'all love ain't even shown
you real they're showing you two seconds
of something that they have curated and
manicured and I'm showing you my hair
crazy I'll be showing you about a pool I
showing you in an alleyway in a gown
after getting kicked out of a party and
yet that's not being lauded by so many
people but I will say with this book the
book tour like the signings have been so
beautiful because when you get in front
of like actual humans they remind you
because you get the but you get the the
bum-rush of love instead of the bum-rush
of hate well and it's in a real energy
space it's not coming behind like you
know Slick Rick 2:25 who's you know a V
is you know a cig a frog smoking a cigar
telling you like you dumb [ __ ] who the
[ __ ] do you think you are
but I need to just say like there's a
lot of narratives about me that are have
been spread this year and it's been wild
because in the same time the beginning
of the year you asked me like yo like
how excited are you that this is
actually happening with your special how
happy are you and I cried and when I
cried I cried not just because I was
relieved that I was finally getting to
do this but also because I knew that
what the fame was about to come a whole
bunch of [ __ ] that I don't it's only
gonna get worse new levels new Dell but
it's only gonna get worse even now after
this book comes out it's gonna gonna get
worse like that's gonna happen
I know but people but when you're
dealing with the transition into that in
front of people yes
yeah there's no rulebook to it there's
no manual that tells us how to handle
this [ __ ] you know especially in this
era I do want to ask one thing you know
people to watch this nip like okay
Amanda said you know these are the
reasons but what do you think you did to
that young lady for her to feel that way
towards you I have no idea really I have
no idea I don't have you spoken to her
since no we haven't had a chance to
speak but I've opened up the space for
it not you what do you call say
something me I think put us we're not
even gonna acknowledge that individual
cuz he did that so they
no but know that I have looked out for
him many attempts IV I had a
conversation enough there's no
conversation to have I have looked out
though
I'm good in my in my karma my karma is
good when I saw that I thought it was
really Gaeta I did gator
yeah I thought it was no I mean you know
people do things for whatever reasons
right but like I feel like if you have
my phone number like we you know we
shouldn't have to do that on on the
Internet's and I've had like one of my
biggest regrets is I should have hit
Chrisette Michelle directly I shouldn't
I hit her in it
I shouldn't have acknowledged that
anything you know her I know her enough
to call her and I'll call her out so
that's a regret I have I should have
done that
what other regrets doesn't man Justin's
have tell me sometimes Amanda Steel's
know she has gotten in our own way
that's another thing they say about a
man see the man is always getting in her
own way yeah but no one tells you how
yes about what you're doing what does
that look no one can ever in your way
difficult I'm like what does that mean
they say she doesn't listen and I'm like
okay so let's so I have to listen to
everybody all the time in order to be
considered not difficult yes that's what
they say but that's not true because a
lot of advice is good advice and I
listen to that you've both given me good
advice
and shitty advice both of you so you
told us both when we're giving good
advice and by the way when I give you
good advice I'll be like you know and
you both asked me for advice and I feel
like I've been on the I've been on the
note sometimes I thought it was you
wanted a reason I thought of going to
third thank you cuz you literally
talking to a couple few years ago she
was like black men do not want to
acknowledge that they're damaged they
don't want to acknowledge their trauma
and they don't want to do the work to
fix it and I was like well I'm gonna
prove Amanda wrong that means a lot to
me that you even wanted to prove me
wrong I think that black men get mad at
me for saying stuff like that because
they think it's a challenge you think
they think it's a an accusation of
blaming pointing finger thing and really
what it is is a plea cuz it's like we
want y'all to be healthy and happy and
winning so bad because so many of us
want to be with you so bad and in order
for that to happen we need you to be
healthy and we need you to be clear and
we need you to have self-knowledge and
self-love how can I expect you to love
me if you don't love yourself like basic
and I just I just don't I mean one of
the most hurtful things to me is this
narrative that I hate black men it's so
wild and it's B and that it's based on
like me calling out a brother that all
of a sudden means I hate black men it's
like I also love like women and I also
love our community and I would much
rather us call us out then wait for the
others to call us out we should have had
to wait for our Kelly to be prosecuted
by some other means we should have just
handled that internally you know and I
think that's something that I really
feel strongly about like I feel strongly
about the fact that like we are a
community we should be able to police
each other without having to call the
police and I think that that comes on
moral standing and ethics and and us
having a communal understanding I'm like
right and wrong and we've gotten so far
from that but I what do you think I
think I've gotten in my own way by being
more honest than I needed to be in
certain situations like being being more
vocal than I needed to be in certain
situations though we got the microphone
we got the platforms like yes I think
people want to hear from we really do
you know and sometimes it's like but no
I think that I've gotten in my own way
by also having a naive perception of the
room and thinking I'm in a safer space
than I really am and just kind of like
being more open than I needed then I
should have been like I don't think I'm
as strategic as I should be and I think
that's really the crux when people say
she's getting in her own way it's like a
man who thinks she's asleep and it's not
and that's how I end up getting in my
own way a lot of times it's like I'm not
operating like it's not even chess or
checkers I'm just like romping through a
field of creativity and forgetting like
but they're playing chess so maybe you
should stop frolicking and sit down and
make sure that they don't take your
queen
but listen do we need to play games with
each other no that's my thing
do black people need to play in no type
of game would and I would love with we
would stop cuz I don't and that's why I
get hurt all the time yeah because I
don't the last time he was he was here
and your man with you
What did he say about it was he
supportive when all the stuff was going
on he shot the club he was great okay
that's the most important tonight that's
all he gets
damn be okay
but you know I like what you say just
that this conversation to me is black
people we have to find a way to continue
to be real with each other teach each
other empower each other but not hurt
each other if we disagree with each
other's heart but like even even when
you criticized life Jennings any song
right he was really upset and he felt
like yo they're trying to play but when
he came he would like that's her opinion
that's his opinion that's people's
opinion he feels like because he's a R&B
artist and he's has history in the game
he feels like you shouldn't be able to
talk about that's incorrect because he's
an artist he has so much skin in the
game I think it's fair for us to have a
certain level of expectation for his
awareness of what his art does and how
it can reach people and this is a song
that if it's about S&M it was misleading
because the references were not S&M
references they were slave references
that's a fact I just
and honestly I told him I it's not even
about the content to me there's nothing
like it
and then I also just feel like he's a
better songwriter yes you know it's and
I think that at the end of the day to
never forget I'm a comedian and it was
funny hilarious he was doing things in
that song that we're funny hot like a
frog Shuma thing like that like we're
gonna act like that's not funny
hilarious bars biggety biggety King like
donkey donkey kong like that's funny dog
like you I was that's what I was he said
it was bars I thought it was hilarious I
thought Amanda's reaction video was
hilarious
posted minute reaction video I had no
idea whose song that was but when I
found out I'm like damn I said laughs
you better than that look but he gets to
be I mean listen if you're artists
you're sensitive about your [ __ ] so I
understand why you would be hurt about
that and there's a difference between
people being critical of your art and
being critical of your character you
know because if they're judging your art
based on like I'm lunch I didn't judge
him as an artist I judged a song right I
didn't say like life genna's is the
ain't shape artist who's out here
wasting a sign that's a whole different
conversation that's the conversation
that people have in about me like people
who don't know me be like that's that
[ __ ] get her the [ __ ] out of here shut
that light-skinned yella [ __ ] down shut
her down and I'd be like why are y'all
so ardent about this I'm also not gonna
be shut down but that was a song it's a
song like if you don't like my book
you don't like my book that doesn't mean
you have to not like me maybe I just
didn't hit it for you this go-around you
know what I really realized people
really didn't like you why people take
it the wrong way when when you had an
incident and you talked about a man that
you felt was taking advantage of woman
right and you said you know I'll put
women I'm gonna put my women on so they
know it what to expect so they can look
out for themselves and women came it was
like nah [ __ ] her she's a [ __ ] liar
and I'm sitting like all she's trying to
do is put y'all off - what happened to
her and what she heard and I was like
the fact that women are coming at it and
Amanda now saying nah [ __ ] that she's a
lie I'm like I'm like damn it man like
you can't even help somebody you can't
even save somebody or try to save
somebody then it went it went crazy you
should just say I'm glad you saw it that
way Envy don't even I am I'm really glad
you saw it that way I saw it the same
way but does it stop me from loving my
people see that's it this this is the
trippy part hmm for everybody that don't
like me I still gotta love you though
like I still love my people cuz you know
better cuz I know better and I know that
there are reasons you don't like me that
were handed down to you in some
situations they were literally handed
down by oppressive means so in some
situations that's it and when I say
oppressive means I mean by patriarchy I
mean by
I mean by classism etc you know you
don't like me because I can talk proper
or something you know like if that's a
source of ire for you like I'm like mad
that somebody put it in you that that's
a reason to not like me
cuz that means that you think that I
think I'm better than you simply because
I speak a certain way or because I was
educated a certain way when really all
I'm trying to do is figure out how I can
get enough resources to make that to
make the assets that I was able to have
access to available to more folks you
know but that that that whole situation
tripped me out too cuz I was just like
and that's what I mean by standing in my
own way because sometimes I'm like damn
I just I didn't I didn't check the bus I
thought I was I thought I was doing
God's work by literally just it's a PSA
like this is what was told to me I'm a
vessel and the willingness of people to
call me a liar but to listen to like
some blog writer just bar none it's wow
wow people just write lies Amanda
Steel's lied about where but should you
listen to anybody in situations like
that why should you just take all
information and do what you can with it
like you have to just look at it as like
I have been presented this now it is
something in my file and I keep moving
but we are so in this in this this
opinion based we're not in an
Information Age we're in an opinion age
everybody just forming [ __ ] based on
their own perception and we have like
they're all feeling their own feelings
we have so much resources for
information I have seen people come in
my DMS in the last week telling me to
kill myself or mine kill yourself you
dumb [ __ ] you hate black man [ __ ] you
like furious you know and then you look
on their page and they're like a systems
analyst you know it's not even like I
can say like oh this is some some dude
who don't know no better this is some
ratchet chick who who's just trying to
rile me up no it's a it's a bevy of
people who just decide like they don't
want to do research and I think that
that's a willful ignorance that's a
choice that I would rather wallow in
this neck in this toxicity and mud sling
then actually take a second to disprove
it because I would have more I'm gonna
have more fun slinging the mud than I
will actually know in the truth and that
is scary to me that we would
rather sling mud then actually know the
truth and there's so much truth we need
to know about each other in ourselves
nobody cares about the truth when the
lie is more entertaining and that's
what's trippy to me I'm not that person
I'm always I am [ __ ] scholar and
Mully mother in Scully I might be like
the truth is out there I'm trying to
find it but I wanted my mom was like
yeah sure you should do the Breakfast
Club because you know them people let's
be upset mama come on mama
yeah well that's fam and if people are
upset they're upset but what I what I
love about coming here is I feel like
you have a very diverse audience of
people that watch this and listen to
y'all because y'all are a diverse group
of people and I know that if I want to
like send messaging this is a place that
I will go to I'm not gonna go to
Anderson Cooper you know like I'm coming
here and also it's very important to
know that these conversations happen off
air it's not like this is public
perception and we're trying to make
people be on our side like no we really
trying to do the work like if somebody
comes out to say shot me and you hate
black women I gotta call my my sisters
and be like okay what am i doing to
cause this narrative and sometimes it's
like not a flippin they tripping and
sometimes it's like well actually that
was poor taste and I'm fine with that
and but that makes me go back and
correct my behavior and it makes me be
intentional yes
about how I treat my sisters and uplift
my sisters now here's the trippy thing
though a lot of your ire comes from like
situations that people have watched you
have a lot of this [ __ ] that man coming
at me is situations that people have not
been a witness to so I'm like how
absolutely you see me talk by myself on
an Instagram sometimes I'm angry
sometimes I'm happy sometimes I'm with
the cats you know sometimes I'm singing
a gospel version of slob on mine you
ready for Sunday service you know
[Laughter]
and also really y'all we just letting
this right
what does it we just letting that go
down what don't make me shake my bunny
oh no cuz I'm a villain
alright let's talk about it I'm a
villain you talked about earlier that
I'm a villain
mm-hmm but this brother okay has openly
supported somebody who is a known
villain to our community correct
multiple times in multiple arenas okay
and somehow we are not catching on to
the fact that he has now employed the
the word of Jesus mm-hmm to continue
this narrative it's not like he came
over here and was like my fault y'all
let me start doing Sunday service so I
can repent for the misstep that I took
in going in that direction
well he's these other things that Mister
have a hard one thing though that's my
point he doesn't he has now simply added
in this the spirituality level hmm to
support his troubling problematic
narrative and then he's on a mic saying
things that are not true we don't think
it's genuine I think he genuinely
believes that what he's doing is right I
think it is absolutely wrong I think um
I think that we have seen the word of
Jesus used to sway Minds for centuries I
think it's hard alright it's a slippery
slope when your artists a public figure
because our lives are our commodities
right so whatever we're going through in
our lives we are essentially selling we
put it in our music of work with with
God I we're dealing with mental health
issues I was dealing with relationship
problems of consume so it's kind of hard
that's what he's at in his life at the
moment
of course people have Jesus all in his
musicals i have jesus all in his merch
yeah but then simultaneously at the same
events he's on the mic touting support
for this person he's also you can be
ignorant too you can be you can be
absolutely stupid while your coin dude
is all spiritual journey he said it's a
slippery slope because I believe that
he's failed Jesus and he's found a new
awakening but I love the fact that he's
talking about it in front of people that
might not ever go to chocolate he's
always had Jesus Raju's when his person
is so much more this that's all he's
talking about anything and I can't judge
somebody spiritual journey but I just
think that I think that learning the
lines of the two is dangerous as a
messaging and I think that when you're a
public figure there is a certain level
of awareness that you have to have for
how you're presenting messaging and
those two things happening at the same
time is very reminiscent of a number of
situations that have happened in the
past where we are being fed wrong
information and troubling information on
the same plate as you know Jesus what
about hip-hop do cuz I can be righteous
and righteous I can love [ __ ]
you know 21 savage would still love rap
city like that's our love common or any
of those positive rappers right yeah but
that's not the same thing as standing up
in front of people and trying to tell
them that they should go follow a
traitorous well that's just stupid
he don't even what he's talking about
even when he says things like
Republicans freed the slaves I can say
no but a lot of people don't know that
that's not true I mean it's technically
as true but it's nuanced because they
had a whole different ideology when they
did that yes it's true however it is not
it's true but it doesn't it doesn't
matter like it doesn't push that it
doesn't push the negative leaving it's
there we go misleading I just think on a
basic note like and my son it talked
about this on his Instagram he was like
this is the most dangerous black man
right now it was like I just really feel
like this is the most dangerous black
man because he's hitting us where we a
lot of us are most receptive which is in
our spiritual center and opening that
chakra he didn't use these words but
this is what he was saying opening that
chakra and other stuff is coming in and
it's dangerous it's dangerous that's why
there's a separation between church and
state like I can acknowledge like like
say like I can name all I can do all the
lyrics that slob on my knob at the same
time
I can all of them like proudly you know
but at the same time then at the same
time that I can quote Zora Neale Hurston
yeah you know and I think that there's a
difference between having internal like
like Paco always talks about like I'm
I'm a contradiction but I think that's
just humanity absolutely but I think
that the presentation of his messaging
is contradictory
however it's being presented it as if
it's not contradictory and that is what
concerns me because I think that we like
I said it all connects we're in a time
where critical thinking is now being
seen as treacherous literally people
think that me being a critical thinker
is me being extra me being too much like
me telling the truth is me being a
troublemaker we've seen that before like
we romanticize the past but there were a
lot of people who used to say things
like that about you know Stokely
Carmichael about you epe about Martin
Luther King like all they stirring up
trouble you know and it's like thank
goodness they didn't have the internet
cuz they may have felt this waited you
know they may have been like you know
what I hate I don't even want to try and
deal with all this but I think what
Kanye I man it's just we are if we were
in an era where I felt like people were
more and more inclined to have a more
balanced representation of information I
wouldn't feel so trippy about it but
we're not we are in a clickbait era
where a lot of sites are more interested
in just writing what's going to make
people click than what's going to make
people think
and so therefore like stuff like this is
gonna keep going and I think it has an
adverse I think it's gonna have a very
deleterious effect and we we really
should be concerned because there's an
election coming and this man is
absolutely stumping for this person and
doing it in the name of Jesus yeah well
we love you Amanda
we love you burger can we talk about the
before I go you know well we have been
talking about it because at the end of
the day like the book is my hilarious
and real and direct version of life
advice for anybody that really just
wants to level up with this clear up
misconceptions about Amanda SEOs
everything we've talked about for the
past 40 minutes do
I think reading this book will make
people have a better understanding of
who Amanda feels is if they desire to
yes some people are like committed to
misunderstanding you but I absolutely
feel like anybody can read this book and
get a better idea of my brain and my
heart and my soul and at the same time
and most importantly a better
understanding of their own brain and
their own heart and their own soul and
doing it through laughter because that's
the whole point like my whole [ __ ] is
like how can I use these jokes how can I
be funny to get us like to a higher
plane and if you're not careful people
will make you like trying to come down
to their plane to play down there and
it's like nah I gotta be up here I gotta
be up here and like come up come up come
up like and what's been dope is the
amount of people who have said to me
like that this book has made them laugh
it's made them consider that's my
favorite thing making it just making you
consider like maybe I should think
differently about this you know or has
made them say like like have an epiphany
like oh I didn't I was trying to figure
this out but I have become the patron
saint for difficult women but hey women
come up to me all the time and I like
girl thank you for speaking your truth
because every day in my daily life
it'll be teachers it'll be people who
work in corporate America you know it'll
be mothers like like every day in my
daily life I'm being told that I'm too
direct or I'm too harsh and I'm really
just speaking from the heart and I'm
just trying to get to the core of things
and they're like yo thank you for being
a light and a and a person that is
encouraging that because we need more of
that and because I want to be that and
I'm just like that that makes me feel
good because difficult is a very easy
word to use and dismiss it's like when
[ __ ] call women crazy PETA [ __ ] love
to say she crazy and then you find out
well what is what happened it's like
well [ __ ] I woulda mace you too yeah you
know so when people say like Oh a man is
difficult I always asked like just give
me the grace of asking my side at what
point do you say I don't give a [ __ ]
though 40 we got two more years
you say that until you turn 40 40 is
when I really started giving a [ __ ] yeah
but your dude the processing is
different every woman has told me like
girl I see you gearing up every woman
has told me like they're like you're on
the right path bevy Smith was like honey
this is it you get moving you're getting
there because it's finding that fine
line of what it's not I don't give a
[ __ ] it's what to give a [ __ ] about yes
that's why I met with my life right now
only because what we said earlier I'm
not going to continue to try to make
people who that are committed to
misunderstanding me understand me I'm
not gonna do it and they don't know
what's on this [ __ ] social media is
literally three to four percent of who
we are and they've made it our whole
narratives like literally when wax was
like Amanda's cool like I thought she
would just be yelling all the time but
why she's been around you that's
different he actually knows you like we
know each other three to four percent of
who we are is on social media and that's
what people have the go off and that's
what they use well small doses is out
right now it's way more than three to
four percent of who I am it's a hundred
percent Who I am its 320 pages it took
me a year to write it it's from the gut
the soul is blood sweat and tears and
it's gonna change people's perception
you I know it is books always do when
people actually take the time to read
books about people's I'm telling you I
get that [ __ ] all the time he'll be like
yeah I really thought she was a piece of
[ __ ] books and then I've been watching
the work you've just been doing on
yourself and I believe that cuz they
come in my dreams and say I really
thought Charlemagne was a piece of [ __ ]
and then I read his books like there's
art in here I did all the art in the
book what don't you do I don't lie I
don't like small doses if the broadband
of sales go get it
[Music]